Fay Jackson Smith papers, 1966-1993
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Fay Jackson Smith papers, 1966-1993
MS 379
Smith, Fay Jackson.
This collection contains research notes and a manuscript for Father Kino in Arizona. The research notes include 3x5 cards, as well as notes written in Spanish. Additionally this collection contains materials regarding Smith's Captain of the Phantom Presido.
.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical Note
Fay Jackson Smith co-authored the book Father Kino in Arizona (Arizona Historical Foundation, 1966) with John Kessell and Frances J. Fox. She also wrote Captain of the Phantom Presidio: A History of the Presidio of Fronteras, Sonora, New Spain, 1686-1735, including the inspection by Brigadier Pedro de Rivera, 1726 (Arthur H. Clark, 1993). Smith has spent many years working with the Spanish documents dealing with the Spanish Borderlands, including the translation of archaic Spanish manuscripts.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains research notes and a manuscript for Father Kino in Arizona. The research notes include 3x5 cards, as well as notes written in Spanish. Additionally this collection contains materials regarding Smith's Captain of the Phantom Presido. This includes correspondence about the book, photographs of Smith, illustrations used for the book, photographs and maps not used in the book, a manuscript, and final author pages for this book. This collection also includes computer disks of these manuscripts.
Access Terms
Smith, Fay Jackson
Kino, Eusebio, Francisco, 1644-1711
Rivera, Pedro de, 1664?-1744
Indians of North America - Missions - Arizona
Fronteras (Sonora, Mexico) - History
Jesuits - Pimeria Alta (Mexico adn Ariz.)
Provincias Internas (New Spain)
Mexico - History, Military
Mexico - Militia - Inpection
Container List
- Research notes on Father Kino in Arizona, 1966, No Date (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Research notes on Father Kino in Arizona, No Date (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Manuscript of Father Kino in Arizona, No Date (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence regarding Captain of the Phantom Presidio, including photographs of Fay Jackson Smith, 1993, No Date (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Illustrations for Captain of the Phantom Presidio, 1974-1977, No Date (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photographs and maps not used in Captain of the Phantom Presidio, No Date (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Manuscript of Captain of the Phantom Presidio, No Date (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Final author papers for Captain of the Phantom Presidio, with corrections, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Final author papers for Captain of the Phantom Presidio, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Computer disks of manuscripts, No Date (Box 1, Folder 10)